So how did you break up the UI into smaller components?
Well, you might have thought that this could be two columns, but
then it would be hard to position the elements here. You
could center them vertically within the height of the screen, but it
wouldn't necessarily line up with the temperature views on the left-hand
side. Instead, this looks more like a horizontal linear layout. Then, the
rest of the elements could be laid out by using a vertical
linear layout. The vertical linear layout would have six children. The third
element would be a horizontal linear layout, composed of two children.
The first would be another vertical linear layout with these two texts
views, and the second element would be another vertical linear layout
composed of these two 2 elements. To make the contents of the
screen vertically scrollable, we put it inside a scroll view. Using
a list view here would be overkill, because we don't need to
scale to an infinite number of item and we don't need recycling.
There's a fixed number of fields on the screen, so a scroll
view is the perfect choice. I can show you our implementation for
the fragment detail XML layout. We hard coded some data in the
layout, so that it would show up as a preview in the
Design Pane. At the root of the View hierarchy, we have a Scroll
View. Scroll Views can only have max one child. So we set
that to be the vertical linear layout. Inside of this layout, we have
a text view for the day of the week, the calendar date,
and then a horizontal linear layout. This is followed by the humidity text
view, wind text view and pressure text view. In the XML
code, we see the scroll view with the trial linear layout. We
give it some padding of 16dp, so that the content does
not flush up against the edge of the screen. Then we see
the text views followed by the horizontal linear layout. We specify
layout margin top of 16dp to give it some more space from
the bottom of this text view. Within this horizontal linear layout, we
have one vertical linear layout which has a width of zero and
a weight of one. And another linear layout with the
width at zero and a weight of one. That means that
both of these children have equal width. For this linear layout,
we specified gravity to be center horizontal. That means that the
contents inside of it will be centered horizontally, which includes
the icon, as well as the forecast text view. Lastly, we
have the remaining text views for the other weather details. When
the layout looks good, we update the detail fragment. At this
point, we also move it into its own file. In the
onload finish method, we used to have a lot of Find You
by ID calls. However, we can cash those views earlier so that
we only have to fetch them once. In the onCreateView method, once
the view is inflated, we can go and find a reference
to all the views we'll need later. We store these views as
member variables in a class. Which is why they start with the
letter M. In the onCreateLoaded method, we make sure that the projection
that we're requesting from the content provider contains all the information
that we need. Especially the new fields that we just added views
for. Then in the onload Finish method, we get the cursor
back with the data we need. We read the weather condition ID
from the cursor. And we're going to need this later to determine
the right icon. But for now, we can just use a placeholder
icon. We continue reading from the cursor and updating the views such
as for the date and description and temperatures. For the new views
for humidity, wind, and pressure, we read the
information from the cursor, and then we format it
properly for the UI. This involved copying over
the strings and the utility method from the gist.